<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rds on ⚡️Bolaji Ayodeji⚡️</title>
    <link>https://bolajiayodeji.com/rd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rds on ⚡️Bolaji Ayodeji⚡️</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 13:22:14 +2400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://bolajiayodeji.com/rd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing GitHub Linguist</title>
      <link>https://bolajiayodeji.com/rd/introducing-github-linguistic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 13:22:14 +2400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bolajiayodeji.com/rd/introducing-github-linguistic/</guid>
      <description>The files and directories within a repository determine the languages that make up the repository. With GitHub, you can view a repository’s languages to get a quick overview of the repository. But how does this happen? What powers this repository language overview?
In this article I would:
 Introduce you to GitHub Linguist How it works How to fix common Linguist issues How to use gitattributesto overriding Linguist :) How to use Emacs or Vim modelines to override Linguist How to contribute to GitHub Linguist  Let’s Roll!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The GROWTH MINDSET demystified</title>
      <link>https://bolajiayodeji.com/rd/the-growth-mindet-demystified/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 13:22:14 +2400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bolajiayodeji.com/rd/the-growth-mindet-demystified/</guid>
      <description>I can&amp;rsquo;t do it, I can&amp;rsquo;t learn this, it&amp;rsquo;s too hard, Come on, I&amp;rsquo;m just a Junior Developer, WebPack is not my thing, I tried it and failed.
Those are the words of a developer drenched and soaked with imposter syndrome.
Over time we keep fighting ourselves, trying to run away from our shadows, trying to find shortcuts, yes I did also, I really did :(
At a point in my life, I just felt some things were not meant for me, I felt maths was too complex for me, JavaScript was not my thing!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTTP status codes and their meanings</title>
      <link>https://bolajiayodeji.com/rd/http-status-codes-and-their-meanings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 13:22:14 +2400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bolajiayodeji.com/rd/http-status-codes-and-their-meanings/</guid>
      <description>Often time, we come across several errors while surfing through some websites which displays with a status code, as developers we need to be familiar with this status codes.
In this article, I&amp;rsquo;d be explaining what each HTTP status code stand for.
What is an HTTP status code?
For every request from a web browser the server responds with a status code. If there was a error, you can get additional information about the error.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>