<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>⚡️Bolaji Ayodeji⚡️</title>
    <link>https://bolajiayodeji.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on ⚡️Bolaji Ayodeji⚡️</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 13:22:14 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://bolajiayodeji.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to JavaScript Switch Cases</title>
      <link>https://bolajiayodeji.com/js/introduction-to-javascript-switch-cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 13:22:14 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bolajiayodeji.com/js/introduction-to-javascript-switch-cases/</guid>
      <description>In this short article, I will introduce you to JavaScript switch cases and how to use them with practical examples.
PS: This article is not for those without any JavaScript knowledge, it is expected that you&amp;rsquo;re taking some tutorial or course and you just got to the switch cases section.
This article will explain better with more practical examples to help you understand switch cases in depth.
Prerequisites.  Basic JavaScript knowledge Code editor Web Browser Your brain :)  A switch statement can basically replace multiple if checks in JavaScript.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to redirect HTTP to HTTPS Using .htaccess</title>
      <link>https://bolajiayodeji.com/op/how-to-redirect-http-to-https-using-htaccess/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 13:22:14 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bolajiayodeji.com/op/how-to-redirect-http-to-https-using-htaccess/</guid>
      <description>Chrome and Firefox have started showing insecure warnings on sites without SSL certificates. Without SSL, your website will show insecure to the visitors. Therefore, using an SSL-encrypted connection for safety, accessibility or PCI compliance reasons is necessary. It becomes very important to redirect from HTTP to HTTPS.
What is SSL? SSL (Secure Sockets Layer) is a standard security protocol for establishing encrypted links between a web server and a browser in an online communication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTTP status codes and their meanings</title>
      <link>https://bolajiayodeji.com/rd/http-status-codes-and-their-meanings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 13:22:14 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bolajiayodeji.com/rd/http-status-codes-and-their-meanings/</guid>
      <description>Often time, we come across several errors while surfing through some websites which displays with a status code, as developers we need to be familiar with this status codes.
In this article, I&amp;rsquo;d be explaining what each HTTP status code stand for.
What is an HTTP status code?
For every request from a web browser the server responds with a status code. If there was a error, you can get additional information about the error.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to test a Pull Request locally before Merging.</title>
      <link>https://bolajiayodeji.com/vc/how-to-test-a-pull-request-locally-before-merging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2018 13:22:14 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bolajiayodeji.com/vc/how-to-test-a-pull-request-locally-before-merging/</guid>
      <description>In this tutorial, I would show you how to check, test and make changes to a pull request before merging.
Recently I dived into OpenSource development which i&amp;rsquo;m super psyched about now. I had some projects I made public and OpenSource on GitHub
Recently i started receiving pull requests and this was pretty awesome and encouraging. A great way to start the party
One major problem I had was how to test this pull requests, I had to use the local &amp;ldquo;copy and paste&amp;rdquo; method to test and run this pull requests before I merged them, this was really stressful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to convert GitHub Markdown files to a simple website</title>
      <link>https://bolajiayodeji.com/vc/how-to-convert-github-markdown-files-to-a-simple-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 13:22:14 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bolajiayodeji.com/vc/how-to-convert-github-markdown-files-to-a-simple-website/</guid>
      <description>Easy Markdown to GitHub Pages Introduction This little guide demonstrates how to turn any Github repository with a bunch of Markdown files into a simple website using Github Pages and Jekyll.
 You don&amp;rsquo;t need to use the command line or anything other than your browser. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t require any knowledge in Jekyll. It&amp;rsquo;s completely compatible with any bunch of markdown files you already have in any existing repository without any modification to those files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to JavaScript Switch Cases</title>
      <link>https://bolajiayodeji.com/dt/introduction-to-javascript-switch-cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 13:22:14 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bolajiayodeji.com/dt/introduction-to-javascript-switch-cases/</guid>
      <description>In this short article, I will introduce you to JavaScript switch cases and how to use them with practical examples.
PS: This article is not for those without any JavaScript knowledge, it is expected that you&amp;rsquo;re taking some tutorial or course and you just got to the switch cases section.
This article will explain better with more practical examples to help you understand switch cases in depth.
Prerequisites.  Basic JavaScript knowledge Code editor Web Browser Your brain :)  A switch statement can basically replace multiple if checks in JavaScript.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>